RYAN KELLEY

138 Ridgeline Dr, Weatherford OK 73096 | 580-583-9654 | rpkelley@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with over 10 years' experience designing, architecting and delivering business- changing software. These projects range from manufacturing and inventory management to oilfield business software yielding customers over \$12 million in savings. But above all I've been a champion of agile and LEAN development and a proponent of modern technology stacks and open source. I believe continuous improvement, testing and continuous delivery are the right way to build software and am looking to join a team that shares the same values I do.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages

- · Lethal: C#, .Net Framework, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL
- · Dangerous: PHP, Ruby, C++, Visual Basic

Software

· Amazon Web Services Stack, Git, Redis, MySQL, SQL Server, Project Management, TeamCity, Jenkins, HipChat, Office, Ansible

EXPERIENCE

March 2010 -Present

Director of Development, Nine Collective

- · Convert 4 year old .NET version of the platform to Node.js fully utilizing Amazon Web Services for scalability, reliability and performance.
- \cdot Recruit and lead team of developers building Fieldbook ERP, a cloud based ERP solution for oilfield services companies.
- \cdot Designed and built several internal tools for project management, testing, builds and deployment.
- · Head architect and software engineer for all projects at the company

February 2009 – March 2010

Senior Software Engineer, Coaches Aid Corporation

· Architected from the ground up a nationwide high school sports content and rankings platform including statistics delivery and community fan engagement.

August 2008 – January 2011

Adjunct Professor, Southwestern Oklahoma State University

• Focused on software development life cycle while teaching courses on software engineering, networking, database systems and project management.

July 1999 – February 2009

Director of Information Services, Freightliner Specialty Vehicles - SportChassis

- Designed, built and delivered a manufacturing management platform leveraging the company's use of LEAN manufacturing.
- Architected and delivered automated inventory replenishment system between warehouse and manufacturing line.
- Designed, built and delivered a service management system, tying inventory with previous production information to provide a better experience for service personnel and customers.
- When company was purchased back from Daimler Chrysler, I oversaw and engineered the entire IT infrastructure upgrade to include networking, databases, firewalls, email services and security.

EDUCATION

May 2007

Bachelors Computer Science, Southwestern Oklahoma State University

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Family

- · Wonderful Wife of over 13 years
- · 5 Awesome Children

Boy Scouts of America

- \cdot Focusing on youth leadership and development by serving as Scoutmaster for Boy Scout Troop 355
- · Eagle Scout
- · Woodbadge Trained
- · NYLT Assistant Scoutmaster

Hobbies

· Mountain Biking, Hiking, Camping, Snow Skiing, Snow Boarding, Board Games, Video Games